photodeck.com 2010-11-13

# Privacy policy | PhotoDeck™ e-commerce photography websites for photographers

Your privacy and the safety of your personal data have great value to PhotoDeck.

## Data collection, storage and processing of personal data

PhotoDeck collects, stores, processes and transmits user data in order to fulfill the PhotoDeck Service, to guarantee that PhotoDeck complies with applicable laws, and to protect the legitimate business interests of PhotoDeck. The collection of personal information submitted by users is a mandatory requirement in the use of the PhotoDeck Service.

PhotoDeck does not store credit card numbers.

Collected personal data is stored on servers located in Europe or in the United States of America. Extensive security safeguards are in place to protect the data against unauthorized access and abuse. The software used on the servers is frequently updated to stay abreast of the latest security developments.

## Access to personal information and sharing with 3rd parties

Access to personal information that can be linked to a specific individual is limited to a handful of authorized PhotoDeck staff. PhotoDeck will not transmit personal information to third parties other than PhotoDeck Subscribers unless explicitely permitted by the individual, due to legal obligations, or when it is an obvious requirement in fulfilling the PhotoDeck Service (e.g. personal information of an individual using a PhotoDeck Subscriber website operated under the PhotoDeck Service).

The use of personal data (e.g. email address) for marketing and promotion purposes is subject to prior agreement (opt-in) with the user.

PhotoDeck might provide selected partners with information about its Subscribers and Users, only when the Subscriber/User has consented to it through the service interface and has been informed of the type of data shared.

## Usage of PhotoDeck Subscribers’ websites

PhotoDeck collects personal data on behalf of its clients (Subscribers) operating websites under the PhotoDeck Service, and makes this data available to the Subscribers operating said websites. Data within this scope include for example User’s approximative location, images stored in lightboxes, orders and transaction information.

## Cookies

The PhotoDeck Service uses cookies to store user authentication data, preferences and offer a better browsing experience. 

A PhotoDeck-powered website can be used with cookies disabled, at the price of a more limited or less friendly experience (the cart and lightbox features require cookies). The PhotoDeck Service to Subscribers for the management of their PhotoDeck-powered website cannot be used without cookies (used for authentification purposes).

The PhotoDeck Service also makes use of temporary session variables, e.g. for authentication purposes or to store the contents of a user’s cart. 

## Statistics and logs

PhotoDeck uses Google Analytics, a service provided by Google (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA) to gather statistical information about PhotoDeck users and visitors. In addition, PhotoDeck collects logs of actions performed on the PhotoDeck website and on the PhotoDeck Service, for technical and security purposes. PhotoDeck access logs include data on the user’s browser and its operating system, as well as IP address.

Similarly, PhotoDeck provides to PhotoDeck Subscribers the opportunity to use Google Analytics and access logs for the website they operate under the PhotoDeck Service. Logs provided by PhotoDeck to its Subscribers do not include IP addresses.

Logs are cleared on a regular basis.

## User rights to access to personal information

Visitors and users of PhotoDeck website and Service can request access to any information held about them and its origin; any recipients of their data and the reason for the storage of such data. This information will be provided free of charge.

Responsible for personal data: J-F Maion
